AYESHA MUKHTAR



+923362044790 Avesharao5195@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Desire to be a part of vibrant and leading organization and create footprints as a Quality Assurance Engineer, to assist the organizations in all aspects by utilizing all my skills, knowledge, abilities and experience with a balance of hands-on management and leadership responsibilities.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER

Freelancer

Jan, 2020 - Present

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Create detailed, comprehensive and well-structured test cases of application/website.
- Perform manual testing of application.
- Perform thorough regression testing when bugs are resolved.
- Maintain the track of bugs and update overall status on daily basis.

SOFTWARE QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER

Softronic Systems (pvt) Ltd, Karachi Feb, 2018 - Sept, 2019

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Review requirements, specifications and technical design documents to provide timely and meaningful feedback
- Create detailed, comprehensive and well-structured test plans and test cases of ERP based Application.
- Estimate, prioritize, plan and coordinate testing activities
- Perform manual testing of application.
- Design, develop and execute automation scripts using open source tools
- Perform thorough regression testing when bugs are resolved
- Maintain the track of bugs and update overall status on daily basis
- Maintain the Quality of Application / forms
- Configuring Applications for Continuous Integration/ Continuous Deployment (CI/CD)
- Deploying applications on client server (VM, CLOUD, Azure) via CI/CD

- Database level configurations (creating Maintenance Plans, Email Configurations, Jobs creation)
- Database schema Comparison and Synchronization
- Automating SQL Scripts execution.

INTERNEE - ANDROID /JAVA DEVELOPER

Nest I/O, Karachi April 2017 – July 2017

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Developed Android Application for the startup.
- Add the chat feature in their web application having Java at backend and HTML at front end.
- Add some chat feature in the web, which was developed using WordPress

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Deliver quality controls and enhancements to proactively address problems and improved product quality, manufacturing flow, customer satisfaction and bottom-line results
- Domain knowledge of ERP Systems / Testing on ERP System
- Possess excellent communications skills and team oriented with proven leadership capabilities with proven ability to integrate out of the box thinking & problem solving analysis to improve processes, systems, and methodologies.
- Creating Test Plans, Cases & Processes
- Performance / Load / Stress / Regression / Penetration Testing
- User Acceptance, UI & Compatibility Testing
- Ability to manage and perform QA/QC process.
- Coordinate and Interact with Development & Design team to reduce the Failures
- Research and Development in new tools and testing processes
- Knowledge of agile development processing and web-based testing applications
- Fluent in Database level configurations.
- Worked on Azure Managed Database Instance.
- Configuring applications for CI/CD (Continuous Integration/ Deployment) in TFS.
- Deploying applications via CI/CD on different server like Azure, CLOUD.
- Perform Database Schema Comparison and Synchronization.
- Know how to execute SQL Server scripts using PowerShell file and how to configure it for CI/CD.
- Knowledge of Android Development.
- Skilled in interpreting technical and business objectives and challenges
- Capable to learn and apply new technologies

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Visual Studio Executing SQL scripts automatically
- Acunetix Penetration testing Tool
- RedGate SQL Compare Data Synchronization Tool
- Selenium Automation Scripts Creation / Execution
- Languages: C, C#, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Database: SQL Server, MySQL
- Softwares MS Office, MS Visio, Android Studio, Visual Studio, NetBeans
- Operating System: Windows 2000/XP/Vista7, 8

EDUCATION

JINNAH UNIVERSITY FOR WOMEN

BS- SOFTWARE

ENGINEERING 2014- 2017

CGPA: 3.3

GOVT. DEGREE COLLEGE FOR WOMEN BLOCK M, NORTH NAZIMABAD INTERMEDIATE

2013

BGrade

USMAN PUBLIC SCHOOL

MATRICULATION

2011

A - On e G r a d e

SHORT COURSE:

SAP (BASIC AND NAVIGATION)

PERSONAL PROFILE

• Father's Name : Mukhtar Ahmed Rao

Date of Birth: Jan 5, 1995

Religion : Islam

Nationality : Pakistani